

JOHN ZHAO

Location: Los Gatos, CA 95032 Email: <u>john.zhao@sunvalle.net</u> Contact: 408-621-2926

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

More than 29 years of hands-on experiences in computing System, Application, Networking, Security and programming environments, lead large-scale technical projects, working with internal staff and vendors to define requirements, scope technical efforts, determine solutions, and then implement those solutions. Expert technical skills in UNIX/Linux Systems/Application build/support and development large DC on-prem/Cloud VPC integration laaS, PaaS, laC, docker/Jenkins /k8s CI/CD/Automation with Terraform/Ansible on KVM/AWS/GCP/Azure, Python(OS/System/DB/Web Interfaces/networking/automation/data science integration, Critial data encryption/recovery, Hard-working, good team management, self-motivated, well-organized and able to work effectively under pressure on demanding environment.

TECHNICAL KNOWLEDGE

GitLab / GitHub / Jenkins / CI / CD/ Cloudformation /Terraform / Ansible, Kubernetes / Docker, UNIX / Linux /Windows/MacOS/WinAD-SFU, Oracle / MySQL / SQL, LDAP / KDC / NIS / IPA, SAN / NAS/Transparent Proxy, Strong Bash Shell Scripting with C/C++ / Python Package management, J2SE / J2EE /Apache / TLS, SQL / PL / SQL, Jumpstart / Kickstart / KVM, Grafana / Splunk / Data Dog/ Dynatrace

HOBBY & INTEREST

Classical Guitar | HiFi Audio

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION AND CERTIFICATION:

- Southeast University, China B.E. Electromagnetism Field & Microwave 1986-1990
- San Diego State University, California USA B.S. Computer Science 1992-1996
- Caltech Post Graduate Program in DevOps 2022 Mar-Dec

Other: Singapore Citizen | US Green Card holder

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Sunvalley Computer Inc. (02/1999 to present) System Software Engineer – Lead SRE/DevOps Bay Area, California, United States & Singapore

- Invented Zero Trust DevOps Automation (High secure Crytocurrency level)
- System Software Engineer Lead SRE/DevOps/IT Engineering consulting for US custormer
- Unix/Linux/DB security audit, migration & data recovery over on-Prem and cloud
- Costomize Server hardware/firmware with linux system integration automation & encryption



 C++/Python, AI, Data science, ETL/Pyspark, docker-compose, Idap/Kerberos, RestApi, Oauth on Dev & Jenkins, K8s, Java, TDV AWS, Azure DataLake, AAD, next.js,nodejs, AWS cli, terraform, ansible CI/CD on DevOps, Nagios/NRPE, Prometheus/Grafana, Splunk, Dynatrace-AppMon on Monitoring

Consulting supported Clients: Sun Mirosystems, NUS/NTU Com Center, Agilent, NEC, Visa Internationl, DBS Vickers, Orange(French Telecom), Converge Asia, Trend Micro, Polaris Wireless E911, Walmat Labs, Samgsumg SSD R&D labs, FormFactor, Trident Microsystems, HGST, Oracle Cloud, Kroger, Finicast, Apple BI, Cigna

07/1996 – 10/2001: Sun Microsystems Inc: System Software Engineer & Professional service with Singapore & US project 05/2004 – 09/2006: VISA International: Solaris Engineer: with APAC credit services transaction regional deployment 07/2006 – 03/2008: FormFactor Inc: Systems Analyst: building Oracle ERP with Sun Microsystems, Oracle & NetApp SAN/NAS, incharge UNIX/Linux/Storage related platform & services

10/2008 – 02/2011: Trident Microsystems: UNIX Engineer Architect creating enginnering services between Santa Clara/Munich with high security, incharge global sorce control repo & UNIX/Linux automation

04/2011 - 11/2014: HGST: Principle Engineer: take over IBM DCE/DFS services, create AWS cloud service & Linux as solution 11/2014 - 03/2019: Principle engineer- Lead SRE/DevOps: support Walmat labs, Samgsumg SSD R&D labs, Oracle Cloud US/UK region

04/2019 – 02/2022: Kroger: Sr Software engineer – Lead SRE/DevOps: creating ecommerce innovation platform with AWS/GKE/Azure & develop python backend services

02/2022: Principle engineer – Lead SRE: Data platform services automation, python, data lake, terradata, Fintech securities support Finicast, Apple BI, Cigna

Advanced Network Technology Laboratories Pte Ltd (11/2001 to 05/2004) Regional Tech Support (Linux networking & security product after sales) Singapore

- APAC regional technical support for ISP customer (Linux based networking & security product)
- Remote system upgrade & License activate over SSH tunnel

Ascom Technologies (06/1995 to 02/1999) **Tech Support (Singapore Gov Computing Solution Provider)**Singapore

- Singapore Gov Computing Solution Provider (Software from UK, Mainfrain Hardware from USA)
- ProC, UNIX/HP-UX/Solaris systems, security & databases services

Tsann Kuen Trans-National Group (07/1990 to 01/1992) **Electronic/Automation Engineer** Xiamen, PRC China

Production Technical department, providing service and support for factory production line, IE Engineering around 200 staff plus 3000 production worker in China Xiamen. Designs computerize tester for production pipeline, and automation control support for machine.

REFERENCE (Available on request)

https://www.linkedin.com/in/john-j-zhao-8656698/



https://www.hackerrank.com/certificates/0bf53df1d328/